yha.org.uk 2017-12-24

# Privacy & Cookies

YHA (England and Wales) is committed to protecting your personal information. This Privacy Notice explains how we collect information about you, how we use the information we collect and how you can instruct us if you prefer to limit or change the use of that information.

Please also read our Cookie Policy and our [site terms and conditions](https://www.yha.org.uk/terms-conditions). If you have any questions, please contact us.

If we need to change our Privacy Notice, we will post changes on this page. This Privacy Notice was last updated on 21st November 2016.

Summary

1\. Your consent  
Where possible, we seek your consent before we process your personal information. Where that is not possible, for example if we receive your personal information with a booking from a third-party booking site e.g. Booking.com, we will process your data in accordance with the contract we have in place with the third party.

When you use our websites (which includes our mobile sites, social media or any other online services we may offer) and provide us with personal information, we will seek your consent to collect and use your information in accordance with this Privacy Notice. If you contact us by telephone, e-mail, post or in person then in so doing you provide consent to us collecting and using personal information.

When you provide us with your personal information, it will only be shared with third parties for the purpose of fulfilling your booking or other services you have requested. Your personal information will only be shared with third parties for marketing purposes if you have specifically given us your consent to do so.

Your communication preferences can be updated at any time via our website or by calling or emailing [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#6605131512090b0314150314100f050315261f0e074809140148130d591513040c0305125b33160207120f0801460b1f4605090b0b13080f0507120f0908461614030003140308050315). See the Contact Us page for more information on how to get in touch with YHA.

Where you submit personal information (including information about you or other people) to us, you confirm that you have all necessary permissions and consents to do so and that you have read, and agreed to, the terms of our Privacy Notice.

2\. What information we collect and how we use it  
Where we process your personal information it may be held by YHA (England and Wales) or by any third party company which processes it on our behalf.

If you make a purchase, book accommodation, or donate to YHA, we will need to know some details about you such as your name, email address, a contact telephone number (should there be a problem with your order) and payment details. We may also require information about other people associated with a booking or membership. If you contact us we may also keep a record of this.

We collect this information to allow us, our service partners and our sub-contractors to process your request, remind you of your reservations, provide the services you have requested, and to send you other service-related communications such as newsletters and emails.

As stated in our booking terms and conditions, on arrival at a hostel you will be asked to produce identification which includes a photograph. This ensures that we can meet our security and safeguarding obligations. Copies of your identification will not be retained.

We retain your personal information only for as long as is necessary in order to fulfill the service you requested, to make future purchases easier for you, to tell you about other products and services that may be of interest based upon your purchasing history, and to allow us to understand customer behaviour and inform future product development.

Where appropriate we retain your personal information for as long as is necessary to meet our legal obligations for reporting where these apply (for example, retaining financial records for up to seven years). When your information is no longer required we delete it securely.

We may retain information about customers whose conduct has been anti-social or breached our policies, for the purpose of restricting those customers’ future use of our services.

3\. Information about young people  
We welcome children and young people to our hostels and to our online services, and we take extra care about handling information about young people. However, our online bookings, membership, donation and purchasing services are intended for users aged 16 years and over, so please do not use these if you are under 16 years old.

If you provide information to us about children under 16 years old, then you confirm that you are the parent or legal guardian, or have the consent of the parent or legal guardian. Group leaders should obtain consent from the parent or legal guardian to share participants’ information with us.

4\. Other uses of our websites  
There may be other ways in which we collect and process your information when you visit our websites, for example:

\- we may invite you to complete optional surveys for research purposes  
\- we may offer competitions and other incentives  
\- we may profile our customers to ensure you receive the most appropriate information for your needs, for example to offer information about products and offers most likely to be of interest to you  
\- we may collect details of your visits to our websites (including, but not limited to: traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type) and the pages that you access so that we can improve the websites and your experience of them.

We may use this data to enhance your online experience when you are visiting our websites by providing personalised content based on your previous browsing history. Please see our Cookie Policy for more details.

We may also tailor email content to your interests, based on analysis of the content you have previously read in YHA emails, the purchases you make with us and the pages you have visited on our websites.

5\. Other websites  
We may receive information about you from other websites. For example, if you book accommodation through a travel agent or website. Your use of those websites will be subject to those websites’ own terms and conditions and privacy policies.

Our websites may link to external websites operated by other organisations. If you click on one of these links you acknowledge that your access to such websites will be subject to those websites’ own terms and conditions and privacy policies.

6\. How we protect your information  
We follow good security practices (including appropriate technical and procedural measures) in the processing, storage and disclosure of information which you have given us. We monitor your information where practical to do so to check that it is accurate and up to date.

Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we are able to discuss your membership, bookings or other queries. Our staff and volunteers in our hostels may have the information necessary to fulfill your booking or enquiry, but might not have access to other information you have provided to us.

YHA will never ask you to send online passwords, credit card or bank details by email.

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

7\. Your responsibilities  
We work hard to ensure that your personal data is accurate, up to date and well protected, but to ensure that it remains secure, YHA (England and Wales) asks that you take the following steps to protect your data:

\- Do not click on links from any suspicious emails which appear to be from YHA (England and Wales) in case they are not. If in doubt contact us.  
\- Never respond to an email purported to be from YHA (England and Wales) which asks you to send us your online password, bank details or credit card information (we will never ask for this information).  
\- Do not use the same password for all your online accounts. Please secure your online account with a strong and unique password.  
\- Please update us if your details change so that we can ensure we have the right information for you.

8\. Disclosing information about you to other organisations  
If you enter a YHA competition then we may pass your information to a partner organisation for the administration of the competition. Details of how your information is shared will be provided in the competition terms and conditions.

Some of our hostels are operated by organisations other than YHA (England and Wales). Where you make a booking or enquiry about those hostels, we will pass your information on for the purpose of providing the services or information you have requested.

We may use third parties to process your information on our behalf. We will only transfer your personal information on the understanding that the third party has undertaken to us that they have in place adequate technical and organisational measures to protect that information, will not pass it on to any other party (without our explicit consent and only with valid grounds) and that they will not use your personal information for their own business purposes.

We may release your information to the police or other authorities where we are under a legal obligation to do so.

We may engage with third parties to analyse data about our customers, members and website users in order to provide us with greater insight into customer behaviour for the purpose of informing future product development.

We may also provide anonymous statistics to reputable third parties for the purpose of analysis. These statistics will not include any personal information.

9\. Managing the information we hold about you  
You may, at any time, request copies of information we hold about you, and ask us to correct or delete that information, or to use it in different ways, for example to opt out of receiving emails or newsletters. Our email communications to you will include a link to automatically unsubscribe from further communications.

If you request copies of information about you (a “subject access request”) then we may need to obtain proof of identity from you and an administration fee of £10.00 may be applied.

9\. Contact us  
YHA welcomes your questions and feedback. To contact us about this Privacy Notice, obtain copies of your personal information, or to request that we update, delete or change how we use your information please contact us:

Tel: +44 (0) 1629 592700  
Email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#b4d7c1c7c0dbd9d1c6c7d1c6c2ddd7d1c7f4cddcd59adbc6d39ac1df8bc7c1d6ded1d7c089e4c6ddc2d5d7cd94c4dbd8ddd7cd)

YHA (England and Wales)  
Trevelyan House  
Dimple Road, Matlock  
Derbyshire, DE4 3YH

Company Registration Number: 282555  
Registered Charity Number: 306122  
Registration Number with ICO: Z6434257

### Cookies

Most websites will use cookies to improve your experience of a website by storing preferences, remembering your journey and improving the interaction between you and the website. The cookies we use on our website may change from time to time.

### What is in a cookie?

A cookie is a simple text file that is stored on your computer or mobile device by a website’s server when you visit certain web pages. The server can retrieve adn read the contents of the cookie. Each cookie is unique to your web browser.

### How do we use cookies?

YHA use cookies to keep track of what you have in your shopping basket, and to remember you when you return to our site. Cookies can not harm your computer. When booking accommodation, you’ll need to have cookies enabled. If you don't wish to enable cookies, you'll not be able to use the site properly. We do not store any personally identifiable information such as name, address and email address we create, but we do use encrypted information gathered from them to help improve your experience of the site. For example, they help us to identify and resolve errors.

### Opting Out

By visiting the YHA website, some cookies will already have been stored on your computer. You can remove these and change your browser settings to prevent them being on your computer. If you choose to opt out of our cookies policy it may effect your experience of the website, and you may not be able to book accommodation or fully interact with the content.

### The cookies we use

has_js

| 

JavaScript-enabled users are identified through the 'has_js' cookie set in drupal.js  
  
---|---  
  
NO_CACHE

| 

Sets a cookie when you submit a form ensuring that the server doesn’t send you any cached content while you remain an anonymous users (not logged in)  
  
SESSxxxxxxxx

| 

When you access the website you are assigned a unique ID, or session ID, which is stored in a cookie. The cookie does not contain personal information, but acts as a key to retrieve information from the website.  
  
webform cookie (name varies depending on webform)

| 

Counts the number of submissions recorded in cookies. You are identified by your user login if logged-in, or by your IP Address and Cookie if not.  
  
hostel_overlap

| 

Set if there are hostels in your cart that have the same stay dates to display warnings. Contains only hostel id's e.g. 000041  
  
uid

| 

Required for the Datacash payment gateway. Only stores drupal user id. This is only set for as long as you are in the payment gateway and is then removed.  
  
plusone.google.com

| 

Google +1 sets a cookie for the share this +1 feature  
  
|   
  
#### Google Analytics, Adwords and eCommerce tracking

__utma

| 

This cookie is used to determine unique visitors to the website and it is updated with each page view. Additionally, this cookie is provided with a unique ID that Google Analytics uses to ensure both the validity and accessibility of the cookie as an extra security measure.  
  
---|---  
  
__utmb

| 

This cookie is used to establish and continue your user session with the website. When you view a page on the website, the Google Analytics code attempts to update this cookie. If it does not find the cookie, a new one is written and a new session is established. Each time you visit a different page on your site, this cookie is updated to expire in 30 minutes, thus continuing a single session for as long as your activity continues within 30-minute intervals. This cookie expires when you pause on a page on the web site for longer than 30 minutes.  
  
__utmz

| 

This cookie stores the type of referral used by you to reach the web site, whether via a direct method, a referring link, a website search, or a campaign such as an ad or an email link. It is used to calculate search engine traffic, ad campaigns and page navigation within your own site. The cookie is updated with each page view on the website.  
  
__utmc

| 

Determines whether or not to establish a new session for you.  
  
Google Cookie NID

| 

A unique identifier used by Google applications to store user preference information.
